If you're going to bury the truth, make sure it stays buried.
I Know What You Did Last Summer is a horror, thriller,
mystery film directed by Jim Gillespie.
After an accident on a winding road, four teens make the fatal
mistake of dumping their victim's body into the sea.
Exactly one year later, the deadly secret resurfaces as
they're stalked by a hook-handed figure.
Julie James, played by Jennifer Love Hewitt.
Ray Bronson, played by Freddie Prinze Jr..
Helen Shivers, played by Sarah Michelle Gellar.
Barry Cox, played by Ryan Phillippe.
Elsa Shivers, played by Bridgette Wilson-Sampras.
Max Neurick, played by Johnny Galecki.
I Know What You Did Last Summer is a 1997 American slasher film starring Jennifer Love
Hewitt, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Ryan Phillippe, and Freddie Prinze Jr.
as four teenage friends who are stalked by a hook-wielding killer one year after
covering up a car accident in which they supposedly killed a man.
It was directed by Jim Gillespie and written by Kevin
Williamson, who adapted the 1973 novel.
It is the first in the I Know What You Did Last Summer film series.
Williamson was approached to adapt Lois Duncan's
source novel by producer Erik Feig.
Where Scream, released the previous year, contained prominent elements of satire and self-referentiality, Williamson's script for I
Know What You Did Last Summer reworked the novel's central plot to resemble a straightforward 1980s-era slasher film.
I Know What You Did Last Summer was released theatrically in the
United States on October 17, 1997 by Columbia Pictures.
It received a mixed reception from critics and grossed
$125 million on a budget of $17 million.
The film was parodied in Scary Movie (2000) and is frequently referenced in popular culture, as well
as being credited alongside Scream with revitalizing the slasher genre in the 1990s.
The film was followed by three sequels – I Still Know What You Did Last Summer (1998), I'll Always Know What You
Did Last Summer (2006) and I Know What You Did Last Summer (2025) – and a 2021 television series.
The film explores themes of high school, police, blackmail, fisherman, letter.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.